

Web Design & Development

karenarialin.me karenarialin@gmail.com (408) 627-5860

https://www.linkedin.com/in/karenalin6

I go beyond my job descriptions to design and develop beautiful user experiences. My diverse skills in the UX sphere - design, development, product management, writing, and animation - allow me to approach the user from a variety of perspectives.

Skills

Design: Wireframing, mockups, storyboarding, video editing

Programming: HTML, CSS (Sass),

JavaScript, Python, Git

Software: Illustrator, Premiere Pro,

AfterEffects, Photoshop, InDesign, Sketch,

Balsamiq

Languages: Mandarin Chinese, English

Education

University of California, Berkeley

B.A in Comparative Literature & Music May 2016

Coursework: Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, Foundations of Data Science

Interests

Percussion performance, backpacking, dance, books

Experience

Jr. Product Manager, Rakuten USA

San Mateo, CA, Feb 2017 - present

- -Perform competitive analysis and research in the mobile development platform market
- -Prepare live and recorded demos and presentations as part of customer outreach
- -Test product alongside engineers for quality assurance
- -Plan product vision and break down weekly tasks

Technical Writer, Rakuten USA

San Mateo, CA, Jun 2016 - Jan 2017

- -Documented new features, conducted UI/UX and text reviews for upcoming software releases
- -Designed and wrote user journeys, storyboards, and wireframe mockups for a product demo
- Developed and maintained Python script used to generate documentation
- -Wrote scripts, recorded voice-overs, and designed animations for product demo videos

Multimedia Editor, The Daily Californian

Berkeley, CA, Jan 2016 - May 2016

-Hired and managed a team of 14 music producers and video journalists to produce daily video projects

Multimedia Web, Video, and Music Producer

Berkeley, CA, Sept 2014 - Dec 2015

- -Conducted research and published feature articles, data-driven infographics, and opinion columns
- -Researched strategies for marketing videos on social media
- -Filmed, edited, and published videos and music clips for the Daily Cal YouTube channel at least once every 2 weeks

Webmaster and Marketing Writer, U Music Education

Foundation

Fremont, CA, Jun 2014 - present

- -Design, write, and revise the school's website content, internal policies and procedures, biannual newsletters, internal surveys, brochures, social media posts, and other marketing materials
- Enhanced the school's website and updated it with the most recent schedules, photos
- -Translated documents between English and Chinese for students and parents